Anandu Krishnan Narayanan

Senior Software Developer

Professional Software Engineer with 5 years and 8 months of experience in developing robust code for high- volume business using both JEE stack and open source technology stack under various Waterfall and Agile methodology projects. Involved in design of new business requirements, development, unit testing and deployment.

hello@akncreative.com

Kochi, India

in linkedin.com/in/anandukrishnannarayanan

📘 +91 7558874487

akncreative.com/

github.com/akncreative

COMPANY PROFILE

Senior Software Developer UST Global Inc.

12/2015 - Present

Kochi, India

Worked on different Enterprise applications as a part of modernization of mainframe projects to Java Spring RESTful services and built new applications with micro-services architecture

- Design and implement Java application phases
- Participate in architectural and software development activities
- Test, maintain and recommend application improvements to ensure strong functionality and optimisation
- Recognize the production and non-production application issues
- Facilitate root cause analysis of system issues
- Multi-task and change from one task to another without loss of efficiency and composure
- Make good technical decisions that provide solutions to business challenges
- Eagerness to learn new ideas, concepts, and technologies
- Clearly and regularly communicate with customers and colleagues

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Languages, Framework and Persistence

Java 8, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring Data Mongo, RESTful web services, Microservices, Apache Kafka, Apache Camel, Junit

DBMS

Oracle, MS SQL, MongoDB

Web Technologies

HTML5, XML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular

Operating System

Microsoft Windows XP, Microsoft Windows 8, Microsoft Windows 10, Microsoft Windows 11 Beta, Mac OSX, Linux UBUNTU, Kali Linux

Tools and Utilities

IBM RSA, Clear Case, Eclipse, STS, intellij, Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Postman, Rest Client, Maven, Bitbucket, Git, Jira, Confluence, Bamboo, IP Switch, MongoDB Compass, Oracle SQL Developer, Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio

WORK EXPERIENCE

Server Log Analyzer (01/2016 - 05/2016)

- Java, 1.7, Angular JS, Oracle 10g, Restful web services, HTML, CSS, node JS.
- Reads the log files generated at a server location and updates an interactive UI with all the details from the log thereby severely reducing the time required by the developers to analyze the logs manually.
- Used Apache POI to read server files and parse them.

Shopper Individual Health Insurance Exchange (05/2016 - 11/2016)

- Java 1.7, spring 3.0, Spring Web Flow, JSP, SQL Database.
- The application contains options for shopping & quoting of medical, dental and life insurance plans. User can create and modify applications for the selected plans.
- The application was built on a traditional MVC architecture .Worked on new functionalities and enhancements to existing functionalities for both Java and JSP layers.

Shopper Online Store Admin Console - Individual/Senior (11/2016 - 02/2018)

- Spring 4.1.6, Java 1.7, Junit 4.12, MS SQL.
- Admin console is an admin tool which is used for internal report generation purpose by employees. This was a modernization project which migrated the existing application from SOAP to RESTful.
- Application backend was built in Spring Framework and the front end was developed using Angular 2. Worked as a fullstack web developer.

Commercial Sales Compensation Commissions - Microservice Architecture (02/2018 - 08/2020)

- Spring Boot 2.1.5, Java 1.8, Junit 4.12, Oracle, Mongo DB.
- This project deals with the computation of the Agent commission based on the business criteria. Built in microservice architecture where I was involved in architecture redesign and implementation of configuration services such as discovery, routing, gateway and dependency management.
- Worked on design, development, unit testing and deployment of 18 spring boot and 3 spring batch projects.

Commercial Sales Compensation Agent Data - Microservice Architecture (08/2020 - Present)

- Spring Boot 2.2.6, Java 1.8, Junit 4.12, Oracle, Apache Camel, Apache Kafka.
- This project mainly deals with data handling and conversion from legacy system to the new application. Worked as a part of design team to build new microservice architecture and setup the application framework. Worked with DevOps to create new build and deployment plans and creating new configuration repositories.
- Worked on Apache Kafka and Apache Camel for data processing and handling. Responsible for design and creation of new microservices and maintaining dependency management and versioning.

HONOR AWARDS

1. Client Rewards

Anthem Inc with UST Global

 Client appreciation for delivering Log Analyzer application in three months.

2. Client Reward

Anthem Inc with UST Global

 For independently delivering a batch project using spring batch that can process(read & write) 1 billion data in 15 minutes within 2 sprints.

3. Client Reward

Anthem Inc with UST Global

 For actively participating in design and setup for new microservice project in a very short time.

4. UST Global Reward

UST Global Inc

 Received UST Global Rewards & Recognition award 3 times while working with Anthem Inc.

5. UST Global Reward

UST Global Inc

 A special award for excellent performance while working on a microservice architecture project.

6. UST Global Reward

UST Global Inc

 Multiple awards for the involvement in managing, conducting and coordinating company events.

REFERENCES

Vinod Vaithianathan

"Account Manager - Anthem Commissions"

Contact: vinod.vaithianathan@ust.com - +91 9447366718

Rajeev Gopalakrishnan Menon

"Delivery Manager - Anthem Digital"

Contact: rajeev.gopalakrishnanmenon@ust.com - +91 8156824793

SKILLS

Fnd to Fnd Application Design & Development

Analytical & Problem solving

Analysis & Debuggind

Agile Development Processes & Principles

Testing & Documentation

Ability to learn quickly

Customer Oriented

Communication & Interpersona

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (09/2011 - 04/2015)

Toc H Institute of Science and Technology (CUSAT) . Kochi, India

INTERESTS

Travelling

Coding

Photography

Gaming

Cooking